Guide to the Henry N. Hinckley local history ephemera,1838-1936.
Hinckley, Henry N. local history ephemera, 1838-1936
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Henry N. Hinckley local history ephemera, 1823-1976.
6749
Henry Noble, Hinckley
.3 cubic ft.
Manuscripts, Printed Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Printed and manuscript ephemera relating to canals, commerce and banking, education, politics and elections, religion, smoking, theater, travel and transportation, and technical equipment, primarily in Ithaca and Tompkins County.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Henry N. Hinckley was born in Trumansburg, NY, son son of Henry L. and Nellie Noble Hinckley. The family moved to ithaca and Henry attended Cornell University, graduating with a degree in architecture in 1911. He worked as an architect and for the Thomas Morse Air Craft Corporation. During World War I, he served in the Signal Corps and with the Air Force in France. After the war, he returned to Ithaca and worked as an investment banker, city building commissioner, owner and manager of residential properties, and collector and authority on antiques. After Henry's death in 1969, his house became the Hinckley Foundation Museum. The museum closed in the 1990s.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Printed and manuscript ephemera relating to canals, commerce and banking, education, politics and elections, religion, smoking, theater, travel and transportation, and technical equipment, primarily in Ithaca and Tompkins County.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hinckley, Henry Noble,
Subjects:
Canals--New York (State); Banks and banking--New York (State)--Tompkins County.; Education--New York (State)--Tompkins County.; Political campaigns.; Political collectibles.; Advertising cards.; Theater--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Travel.
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.)--Commerce.; Tompkins County (N.Y.)--Commerce.; Ithaca (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.; Ithaca (N.Y.)--Description and travel.; New York (State)--Description and travel.
Form and Genre Terms:
Trade cards.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Politics: Atlanta Journal's Cabinet Souvenir (broadside), 1876 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Politician's Register (booklet), 1840 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Stratford Convention Committee Report (1 sheet), 1831 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- A. Lincoln photograph (card), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Republican National Convention (guest pass), 1908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- State Legislature members breakfast and parade (menu card), 1919 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- List of 4th Ward, Ithaca, N.Y. candidates (2.8"x 2.2" sheet) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- U. S. Senate Report of the day, February 5, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Woodrow Wilson message calling for war with Imperial German Government in defense of American rights, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 12th Ward Republican Ticket, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Itinerary for the visit of the Members of the State Legislature to the parade of the Twenty-Seventh Division, United States Army, New York City, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Presidential Centennial, Auburn, N.Y. (official programme), 1889 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 26th Congress, 1st Session, Message from the President of the United States (M. Van Buren) at the Commencement of the First Session {3 uncut leaves}, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Laws of New York -- By Authority (Diedrich Willers, Jr.)(1 sheet), 1871 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Nuggets and Crystals from the Public Speeches and Official Papres of Benjamin Harrison (booklet), 1892 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Hood's Political Points (booklet), 1888 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Protection of Home Labor and Home Productions necessary to the Prosperity of the American Farmer, Henry Carey Baird, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- This is United States Greenback, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Harrison and Morton Campaign Song Book of the Republican Party, H. E. Gordon (booklet), 1888 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- History of the Discovery of America of the Landing of Our Forefathers at Plymouth and of Their Most Remarkable Engagements With The Indians in New England, Henry Trumbull (booklet), 1833 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Proceedings of the Liberal Republican Convention (booklet), 1872 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Politics: Speech of Hon. Roscoe Conkling (booklet), 1871 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Speech of Hon. Roscoe Conkling (booklet), 1872 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Acorn Temperance Songs (booklet), 1908 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Garfield and Arthur Campaign Song Book (booklet), 1880 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- An Address to the Friends of the Republican Principle Without Distinction of Party (Town of Ulysses) (leaflet) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Garfield and His Cabinet (broadside), 1885 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Republican National Committee Headquarters receipt for ten dollars, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Telegram (mss., 2 pages), 1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Homily on politics (mss.), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Willkie for President button, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- General Grant pin, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- The National Press (newspaper), 1891 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Republican State Convention (list of delegates), 1891 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Five Dollars in Democratic Wild Cat Money, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Religion: Discourse on The Subject of Truth, as Connected with Regeneration, Rev. William Page (booklet), 1832 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 7 Presbyterian Church sermons(printed and mss. booklets), 1829-1866 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Receipt for thirty dollars, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- notes, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Poems and notes, W. A. van Warrne (sp.?) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- A New Hieroglyphical Bible, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Catechism, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Sunday School items (2), 1863 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Picture Lesson Paper (3 issues), 1909 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- poems (2), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- temperance items (4), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Methodist Episcopal quarterly tickets (3), 1849-1854 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Marriage Seal, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Communion and Baptism, 1846 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Isle of Wigth Bonchurch (photograph) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- The Flight into Egypt (print), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- W. N. Page to Hermon Camp and Nelson Noble (als), 1866 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Scrip (25 cents), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Smoking: cigarette cards (47), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Technical Equipment: Electric door (booklet), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Kodak folder with negatives, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Thermometer leaflet, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Standard scales (card) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Saw vises (card), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Lithography and printing (card) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Binoculars (booklet), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Type Specimens (booklet), 1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Phonographic World [for shorthand and typewriting] (Magazine), 1891 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Theater: programs (8), 1866-1923 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The Theatre Goer! (newspaper), 1891 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Star cards (2), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Travel and Transportation: Pittsfield, Mass. (pocket guide), 1891 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Watkins Glen (souvenir folder) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Cayuga Lake, Ithaca, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Philadelphia (print) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Baltimore (print), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Chillon, Clarens, Switzerland (print) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Heidelberg, Germany (album), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Cayuga and Seneca Lake items (3), 1853 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Pennsylvania Railroad item, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Colorado Railway Association (ticket), 1882 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Baltimore & Ohio Railway timetable, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad Co. ticket, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Michigan Central and Great Western Railways cards (2) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- The Arcade Railway [NYC](card), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Erie Railway Company ticket, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Railroad passes: Addison and Pennsylvania; Bath & Hammondsport; Elmira, Cortland & Northern and Canastota; Geneva, Ithaca & Sayre; Jacksonville & Atlantic; Lehigh Valley; Pennsylvania and New York; Seneca Fall & Cayuga Lake; and United States Express Co. (15), 1885-1889 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Choo-Choo Trains (children's book), 1927 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Catskill & Ithaca Stage card, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Carriages advertisement card, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Turnpike pass, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Steam yacht/steam boat items (3), 1837, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Miscellany: Children's stories, 1835, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Children's items (5), 1888, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Invitations, calling cards (8), 1838-1895 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Receipts (5), 1851-1908 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Ribbons (2), 1888, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Moving notice (1), 1891 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Health and recipes book, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Photo Story of Tri-State's Greatest Flood, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Commercial - Banking, Money, etc.: banks: Tompkins County National Bank, Ithaca Savings Bank, National Bank of Ogdensburg (5 items), 1901-1925 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Insurance: Equitable Life Assurance Society, Metropolitan Life Insurance Company (2 items), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Almanack, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Ledger pages, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Notice of lost wallet, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Sheriff sale notice, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Receipts (5), 1881-192- (Box 2, Folder 1)
- post card, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Advertisements (3), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Education I: printed history of important events in the history of the United States, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Fragment of writing re Jefferson Davis (mss.) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Penmanship books (4), 1838-1839 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- A. Lincoln to Horace Greeley (t[printed]l), 1862 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Education II - Printed items re: Trumansburg Academy, Cooperstown Seminary and Female Collegiate Institute, Cortland Academy, Dryden Seminary, Oswego Commercial College and Telegraphic Institute (5 items), 1858-1865 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Publications from Groton Academy (3), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Rewards of Merit (7), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Receipt (1), 1863 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- List of school district inhabitants, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Commencement programs (2), 1885-1891 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- List of books, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- District School Journal, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Certification of school inspection (2), 1823-1825 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Poems (4), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- "Our school is coming to a close" words for song (mss.), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Education 3: Cayuga Lake Military Academy (booklet), 1893-1896 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Practical hints on football, C.M.J. (booklet), 1891 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Student writings (9 mss.), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Class notes (6 leaves), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- School list (1 leaf), 1858 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Receipts (2), 1858 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Court date notice (mss.), 1846 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Tart Rhymes (booklet) [advertisement], 1904 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Poems (2), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Note of addresses (mss.), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Letter from Mr. Jefferson in possession of Queen Victoria (printed), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- "The Student", 1851 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous over size items: Economy of Horse Power (broadside), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Loan of the City of Philadelphia (certificate), 1861 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Cortland Opera House (Broadside), 1892 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Marriage certificate (certificate), 1871 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Historic Ithaca Greek Revival Festival (Broadside), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)